The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial is a drama, war
film directed by William Friedkin.
Barney Greenwald, a skeptical lawyer, reluctantly defends an officer of the
navy who took control of the Caine from its captain, Lt.
Philip Francis Queeg, while caught in a violent sea storm.
As the court-martial proceeds, however, Greenwald increasingly questions if it was truly a mutiny or
rather the courageous acts of a group of sailors who could not trust their unstable leader.
Lt. Philip Francis Queeg, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Lt. Barney Greenwald, played by Jason Clarke.
Lieutenant Stephen Maryk, played by Jake Lacy.
Commander Katherine Challee, played by Monica Raymund.
Captain Blakely, played by Lance Reddick.
Lt. Keefer, played by Lewis Pullman.
The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial is a 2023 American legal drama
television film written and directed by William Friedkin.
It is based on Herman Wouk's 1953 play of the same name, itself
based on Wouk's 1951 novel The Caine Mutiny.
It stars Kiefer Sutherland, Jason Clarke, Jake Lacy,
Monica Raymund, and Lance Reddick.
The film marks a posthumous release for Reddick and Friedkin, who both died in 2023
on March 17 and August 7, respectively, and is Friedkin's final work.
The film premiered on September 3, 2023 at the 80th Venice International Film Festival and was released
in the United States on October 6, 2023 on Paramount+ with Showtime by Republic Pictures.
The film explores themes of mutiny, navy, based on
play or musical, naval officer, trial.
The tone is dark and emotional.